《傲骨贤妻》前情回顾
Previously on the Good Wife
-格伦  -彼得
- Glenn - Peter
你把我换到集体牢房了
So you put me in the general population.
是的
Yes
麦迪逊小姐
Miss Madison
你认识这名男子吗
Do you recognize this man?
在和我的当事人交往之前
Prior to your relationship with my client,
你曾经和他有过类似的关系
you had a similar relationship with him.
你不会这样对我
You wouldn't.
为了保护我的家庭  我会不择手段
To protect my family, you have no idea what I'm capable of.
这和性丑闻没关系
This is not about sex.
我重申一遍
Now let me repeat that because it bares repeating.
这和性丑闻没有关系
This is not... about sex.
那到底是为了什么
So, what is this really about?
我的当事人获刑入狱
My client was convicted and sentenced to prison
不过为了一个简单无趣的理由
for a very simple and almost prosaic reason.
他让下属对某些案件拒绝起诉
He told his subordinates to dp-- decline to prosecute-- certain cases,
而控方认为他这样做
and the prosecution believes this was in trade
是为了换取金钱或性
for financial and sexual favors.
这就是本案的情况
That... is what it comes down to.
不过控方忽略了一点
But the prosecution has a problem.
他们在审讯时提供的
The evidence that they presented at the trial
仅仅是间接证据  要想获准复议
was entirely circumstantial, and to be granted a new trial,
我们甚至无需去反驳那些证据
we don't even have to disprove any of it.
我们只需让法官大人您相信
What we need to do, what we intend to do, is to persuade your honor
如果陪审团当时看到
that if the jury had heard the new evidence
我们将在未来两周内呈现给你的新证据
that you will hear over the next two weeks,
他们可能会做出截然不同的判决
they likely would have reached a different verdict.
不  我没事
No, I'm all right.
我只是在等开庭辩论而已
I'm just, uh, staying for the opening arguments.
情况怎么样
How is it going?
感觉不错
Good. They feel good.
很好  法官喜欢彼得
Good. The judge likes Peter.
给他个理由  他就会做对彼得有利的判决
He just needs to be given a reason to decide for him.
话说  还得给你添麻烦
Anyway, sorry to be loading up on you,
客户一小时后就到了
but the client's going to be here in an hour.
什么客户
What client?
科林·斯威尼
Colin Sweeney.
我喜欢别人听到这个名字的反应
I love the reaction that name gets.
好像见了鬼似的
It's like the horses in Young Frankenstein.
我们真的要为他辩护吗
Are we really going to represent him?
我们真的要为他辩护
We are really going to represent him.
而幸运的你呢  要做他的次席律师
And, lucky you, you're now second chair.
确实很幸运
Lucky me.
一小时后见
I'll see you in an hour.
客户们会哗变
Clients are going to bolt.
只有你的客户会
Your clients.
那些不付钱的婆婆妈妈的女权主义者
You mean the bleeding heart feminists who don't pay the bills?
别偷换概念  这和女权主义无关
Don't play that game. This isn't a feminist issue.
科林·斯威尼杀死了他的妻子
Colin Sweeney killed his wife.
科林·斯威尼被判无罪
Colin Sweeney was found not guilty of killing his wife.
-当初辛普森也被判无罪  -是的
- So was O.J. - Yes, and...
但为什么只有我力挺"无罪推定"
why am I the one standing up for "Innocent until proven guilty" Here?
因为你根本意不在此
Because you're not.
你不过是想争取他公司的生意
You want his company's business.
对  你也该这样想
Yes, as should you.
斯特恩一走  公司损失了1/3的生意
We lost a third of our business with Stern leaving the firm.
我们没立场对客户挑三拣四的
We can't turn our noses up at any clients these days.
你心爱的案子无法给公司
Because we know we're not making
-带来任何收入  -那不是我心爱的案子
- any money from your pet causes. - It's not a pet cause.
都还没有立案  我只是考虑一下
It's not even a lawsuit yet. I'm just considering it.
得了  你赢不了的
Come on. You can't win.
你根本不是想打赢
You don't even want to win.
你只想找枪械制造商的麻烦
You just want to harass gun manufacturers.
现在就像在大西部  是吧
So, it's the wild west, is it?
斯特恩走后  你有一个表决权
Without Stern, you have one vote,
我也有一个表决权  我们各自为政
I have one vote, and now it's every man for himself?
看起来是这样
Looks like it.
前景不妙啊
We're heading into a bad time.
左轮手枪  半自动式  6发式  8发式
Revolvers, semiautomatics, six-shot, eight-shot.
为了胜诉  我们必须证明这些制造商
To win, we have to show that the gun manufacturer
故意违反了本州法律
knowingly violated state law
因为他们违法分销枪支
when they allowed guns to be illegally distributed.
这里每支枪  都是在2英里以内买到的
Every single one of them was bought within two miles of here.
-都没装子弹?  -嗯
- They're all unloaded? - Mm-hmm.
拉开枪栓  检查枪膛内是否有子弹
Slide the bolt to check for a chambered round.
卸下弹夹  检查枪管
Drop the magazine. Do a physical check of the barrel.
确实没装子弹
You're unloaded.
太奇怪了
It's so odd--
手枪对人的吸引力  近乎原始
The attraction to handguns. It's almost primal.
看起来真酷  颇有萨拉·佩林之风啊
It's a good look-- Sarah palin-esque.
谢谢你
Oh, wow. Thank you.
那一支呢
What about that one?
沃尔瑟PPK  7发式  9毫米口径
Walther ppk, seven-shot, 9mm.
这东西在外面卖多少钱
And how much would this cost on the street?
看情况
It depends.
-这把我花了五十块  -看这把
-That was 50. - Check this out.
-真小  -科林·斯威尼
- It's so small. - Colin sweeney?
听说他奸尸
I heard it was a necrophilia thing.
不  是把他妻子切块  混到狗食里
Nope. Chopped her up. Put her in the dog food.
鬼晓得陪审团怎么想的
Don't know what the hell that jury was thinking.
找不到尸体就很难说服陪审团
Tough to convict when they never found a body.
这是完美的犯罪
It's the perfect crime.
现在还有人用这枪身锯短的枪吗
Do people still use sawed-off shotguns these days
还是已经过时了
or is pass?
为什么让艾丽西娅来接
So, why is Alicia on it?
你知道为什么
Oh, you know why.
上次起诉他的是她丈夫
Her husband prosecuted him the first time.
所以?
So?
谁最适合替他辩护呢
Who better to defend him?
福瑞克夫人  很高兴见到你
Mrs. Florrick. A pleasure to meet you.
别担心  杀死她的是另外那只手
Don't worry. I killed her with my other hand.
玩笑而已
Joking.
抱歉  我去年起开始开这种低级玩笑
Sorry. I've developed a perverse sense of the comic over the last year.
上庭之后  别开这种玩笑  好吗
Okay, well, let's try not to joke like that
你觉得我们需要上庭?
You think it'll come to that-- court?
坎特韦尔是名顶级诉讼律师  他想要上庭
Cantwell is a top litigator-- he wants a trial.
我们的目标是避免让陪审团判决
Our goal is to avoid a jury.
你和辛普森的情况很相似
You're in a similar situation to O.J.,
打个比方  无意冒犯
If you don't mind me continuing the metaphor.
像辛普森一样  你被判无罪
Like O.J., you were found not guilty,
但人们都认为是你干的
but people think you did it,
他们希望你被判有罪
and they want to see you hurt.
你的继女想利用这点
Your stepdaughter is counting on that
因此她才在民事法庭起诉你
That's why she's suing you in civil court.
夏洛特和我一向意见不合
Charlotte-- we never saw eye to eye, I'm afraid.
她恨她母亲为我离开了她父亲
She resented Carolyn leaving her father for me.
不幸的是  伊利诺伊谋杀法令规定
Unfortunately, the Illinois slayer statute says
若你导致某人死亡  就无法继承死者财产
you can't inherit someone's estate if you cause their death.
若夏洛特胜诉  她将得到钱和公司
If Charlotte wins, she gets the money, the company.
你怎么想  福瑞克夫人
What do you think, Mrs. Florrick?
什么我怎么想
What do I think about what?
你的丈夫起诉过我
Your husband prosecuted me.
我是否有罪  你一定有自己的见解
You must have an opinion as to my guilt or innocence.
我的想法无关紧要
My opinion is irrelevant.
此刻它对我来说很重要
Not to me. Not at this moment.
你觉得是我杀了我妻子吗
You think I killed my wife?
当然
Of course.
你雇我们为你辩护...
Look, you pay us to represent your interests...
但没人发现她的尸体
Even though her body was never found?
你想办法处理掉了
I'm sure you found ways to dispose of it.
切成块  然后埋在垃圾坑里  是吗
Chopped her up and buried her in a landfill somewhere?
或者扔进了密歇根湖里
Or in lake Michigan.
那我的不在场证明呢
And my alibi?
你只说你当时正从圣路易斯驾车回芝加哥
That you were driving from St. Louis to Chicago at the time?
看来你不介意为杀人犯辩护嘛
So you have no problem representing a murderer?
我很介意
Oh, I have a great problem with it.
但你还是会帮我  对吗
But you'll do it anyway?
除非你想让我回避
Unless you'd like to exclude me.
当然不想
Oh, not for the world.
很好  既然把话说开了...
Okay, great. Well, now that we've got that settled...
全体起立
All rise.
请坐
Sit down.
科里  给门上点润滑油
Cory, let's get some wd-40 on that.
安静
Calm down.
把相机给我  就是你  给我
Give me that. You. Now.
别藏了  交出来
Don't try to hide it. Now!
我知道  你们对本次庭审都很激动
Okay, now, I know you're all are excited about this trial,
但这不过宗遗产案子
But this is a probate matter, and, as such,
而你们是客  我是主  客随主便
you're just visiting here. I live here. My rules go.
加德纳先生  准备好了吗
Mr. Gardner, are you ready?
是的  法官大人
Yes, your honor.
坎特韦尔先生
Mr. Cantwell?
坎特韦尔在哪里
Where the hell is Cantwell?
我...
I, uh...
你是谁
Who are you?
南希·克罗泽
Nancy Crozier...
法官大人  坎特韦尔先生病了
Your honor. Mr. Cantwell has taken sick,
原告由我来跟进
and the plaintiff has asked me to step in.
阿米塔小姐
Miss Armitage?
在
Yes.
如果你想另找律师
You can request a continuance if you would like to
就可以要求延期再审
look for other representation.
反正被告不计花销
As you can see, the defense has spared no expense.
是的  我知道  法官大人
Yes, uh, I know, your honor,
但我和南希是老交情了
but Nancy and I go way back, and I think
我觉得找个信得过的人比较妥当
I'd rather go with someone I trust.
年纪轻轻的  哪来的老交情
Ma'am, you're not old enough to go way back,
这位律师叫什么来着
But if, uh, Miss... What is it?
克罗泽
Crozier.
但要是你选择克罗泽
Crozier is your choice...
就请克罗泽小姐上来吧
Come on up here, Miss Crozier.
好  坐在那里
Okay. That's where you sit.
趁她没搞清楚状况
Slip in a motion for a bench trial
提请由法官直接审理此案
before she knows what hit her.
法官大人  我方有一请求
Your honor, just a quick request before we begin.
我方充分信任您对此案的判断  因此
We respect your judgment in this matter, and
我方想请求由法官直接审理此案
we would like to ask for this to be a bench trial.
克罗泽小姐?
Miss Crozier?
抱歉  您问什么  法官大人
I'm sorry. Could you...? What was the question, your honor?
他们希望此案由法官直接审理
They would like this to be a bench trial.
他们不想要陪审团审判
They want not to have a jury.
你有异议吗
Do you have an argument?
不知道
I don't know.
既然你不知道  那我就准予被告请求了
Well, if you don't know, then I must decide against you.
法官大人  我只想说一点  我认为
Well, the one thing that I would say, your honor,
由一个成员立场各异的团体来审判
is that... that I do think that it would be fairer
比一人独立审判更公平
to have a cross section of people, not just one.
无意冒犯
Please don't take that the wrong way.
法官大人
Your honor,
我认为  基于法律的审判
I think that it would be... fairer
比基于陪审团的情感倾向的审判
if we decide this matter on the law,
要更公平
not on the passions of a jury.
克罗泽小姐?
Miss Crozier?
这话或许有道理  但我不会试图...
That might be true, but I'm not going to try and, uh...
煽动利用陪审团的情感倾向
rile up those passions.
我只是...  想让他们知道真相
I just... I want them to hear the truth.
你刚赢了你的第一次辩论  克罗泽
Well, you've won your first argument, Miss Crozier.
我们明早开始选择陪审团成员
We'll start choosing a jury tomorrow morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么回事
What happened?
她漂亮  伶俐  年方26
Cute, perky, 26 just happened.
感谢你抽空见我们  布罗迪先生
Thank you for giving us some of your time, Mr. Brody.
你们想怎么样
What do you want?
我们打算传唤你出庭作证
We're going to subpoena you to testify.
你们应该知道  我会是个敌意证人
You do understand I'll be a hostile witness?
我们知道  你以前并无敌意
We understand that you weren't always so hostile.
那是在你堕落之前
That was before you were corrupt.
我们只想告诉你  你的敌人不是我们
I think we're saying that we're not the enemy.
是彼得雇你进州检察官办公室
Peter hired you at the state's attorney's office.
他曾四度提拔你
He promoted you four times.
格伦·查尔兹只提拔了你一次
Glenn Childs promoted you once.
而且以后也不会再提拔你
He'll never let you rise any higher.
他认为你和彼得还有瓜葛
He thinks you have one leg still in Peter's camp.
这就是你们的目的
Oh, so that's what this is about?
-影响我的证词  -不是
- Influencing my testimony. - No.
是让你说出真相  即使对查尔兹不利
It's about getting you to tell the truth, even if it hurts Childs.
我向来只说真相
I have always told the truth.
我认识很多只说真相的人
I know a lot of people who've always told the truth,
然而  我却如此下场
and yet, here I stand.
我问你
Let me ask you something.
挨个法庭追击我妻子  你就满足了?
Are you really fulfilled chasing my wife from court to court?
我尊敬你  查尔兹却把你当跑龙套的使唤
I respected you. Childs has turned you into an errand boy.
福瑞克先生  你雇用了我  我由衷感激
Mr. Florrick, you hired me. I'm grateful for that.
你管理棘手的部门  我也很钦佩你
You ran a tough department. I admire that.
但从你泄密给你妻子以用于法庭那天起
But the day you started slipping your wife information
你就失去了我的尊敬
to use in court, that's the day I lost respect for you...
看起来很忙啊
Seems like a busy room.
他们叫我过来的
They asked me here.
是的  他们也叫我过来
Yes, they asked me here, too.
他们肯定想让我们撞见
They must have wanted us to bump into each other.
凑巧而已
Just a quirk in scheduling.
我叫他们去死
I told them to go to hell.
我相信你
I have no doubt.
这就是叫我来的原因吗
So that's why I'm here?
看马坦离开
To see Matan leaving?
不  打牌三缺一
We needed a fourth in our pinochle game.
下次  打电话告诉我你的战略计划
Next time, phone me with your strategic plan,
我就省得离开办公室了
so I don't have to actually leave my office.
蹩脚的戏码
Poor show.
你觉得起作用了吗
You think it worked?
等马坦作证时  就知道了
I think we'll know more when Matan testifies.
他妻子死后  他竟然没卖掉这些画
You think he'd sell them after his wife's death.
我猜是在他妻子死后才买的
My guess is he didn't buy them until then.
要安装电子监控吗
So, are they going to go with electronic monitoring?
给彼得?  是的  如果上诉成功的话
For Peter? Yes, if he wins the appeal.
孩子们很激动吧
Kids are excited?
是的  不过有点紧张
Yeah... But nervous.
你呢
And you?
一样
Same.
以后会很怪  是吧
It's going to be weird, huh?
你指什么
What do you mean?
我也不知道
I don't know what I mean.
我们说好有空共进晚餐的  是吧
We said we'd have dinner, didn't we?
是的  有空去呗
Yes. We should.
很抱歉让你们久等
So sorry to keep you waiting.
希望你们没什么不自在
You're comfortable, I hope.
卡罗琳失踪后  我卖了房子  搬到这里
After Carolyn disappeared, i sold the house and moved in here.
可惜房子有点狭小
A bit cramped, unfortunately.
按照我的理解
Now, as I understand it,
你们想让我更讨人喜欢
you're going to try to make me more likable.
这是民事诉讼  我们护不了你
Well, in a civil case, we can't keep you off the stand.
你必须出庭作证
You have to testify.
是的  在陪审团面前作证
Yes, before a jury.
真是出人意料
That was unexpected.
法庭经常有出人意料的事
Unexpected things happen in a courtroom,
所以我们要尽量避开它们
That’s why we try to avoid them if we can.
你们担心我出庭时会说些不该说的话
And now you're worried i'll say something unfortunate on the stand like
比如怎么处理我妻子的骸骨
what I did with her remains?
严肃一点  斯威尼先生
Take this seriously, Mr. Sweeney.
如果你珍惜自己的钱  就该严肃一点
If you value your money, you should take this seriously.
谢谢  福瑞克女士
Thank you, Mrs. Florrick.
我知道了  我也的确珍惜我的钱
Of course. And I do value my money,
我会严肃的
So I will.
民事诉讼中  对方律师会穷追猛打
A civil case can get ugly.
他们会对你的婚姻问题吹毛求疵
They can pick apart your marital troubles with a fine-tooth comb.
你和你妻子常吵架  是吗
You two fought a lot, didn't you?
经常吵
Constantly.
我和卡罗琳的关系就像暴风雨
Carolyn and I had a tempestuous relationship.
可我们深爱着对方
But we were devoted to each other,
典型的一个愿打  一个愿挨
classically s and m.
-那是她吗  -是的
- That's her? - Yes.
她讨厌那张照片  所以我把它放大
She hated that photo, so I had it enlarged.
他们会提出证据  证明你与多名女子有染
They will put on evidence that you were unfaithful to her with multiple women.
是真的吗
Is that true?
我有和其他女人上床
Well, I had sex with other women.
卡罗琳不玩把戏  她知道我需要它们
Carolyn didn't do tricks. She knew I needed them,
所以她同意我找别的女人
so she was okay with me going elsewhere.
什么"把戏"
I'm sorry, "Tricks"?
皮装  手铐  穿异性服装...
Leather, handcuffs, cross-dressing...
这让我更讨喜呢  还是相反
Does that make me more likable or less?
近期来  我都忘了这时代的主流了
I've lost track of the zeitgeist these days.
你声称自己还爱着她
But you still claim you were in love?
是的  疯狂地爱着她
Yes, madly.
她的会计在谋杀案的审讯时作证
Her accountant testified at the murder trial
说她当天要求查账
that she demanded to see the books that day,
一查之下  她非常震怒
and something she saw apparently upset her.
她发现
One of the things she saw was this.
你从账上提取了几十万美金
Withdrawals, made by you, for hundreds and thousands of dollars.
我说过  卡罗琳不介意我的小小嗜好
I told you. Carolyn didn't begrudge me my appetites.
有传言说  她有意把你踢出家族生意
There were rumors that she wanted to oust you from the family business.
还有传言说  你默许你丈夫召妓
Yes, and there were rumors you knew of your husband's whores.
出庭最好别这么回答
Probably not the best answer in court.
当你得知妻子的死讯  你说
Is it true that when they told you of your wife's death,
"这下好  桥牌缺人了"  此事是否属实
you said, "Oh, no, now I'll need a fourth for bridge."
是的
Yes.
当保罗得知列侬的死讯
And when Paul Mccartney was told
他说  "真他妈倒霉"
of John Lennon's death, he said, "What a drag."
我不适合作证  是吧
I'm not going to be a very good witness, am I?
没错
No, you're not.
她不是我杀的
I didn't do it.
这语调效果如何
How did that sound?
沃尔库特森  3.5口径
Volquartsen 3.5 compact.
重3磅  10发弹夹
Three pounds, ten-shot mag,
可调表尺  片状准星
adjustable rear and blade front--
见神杀神  遇鬼灭鬼
It'll take down any man in his tracks.
如果她没有持枪许可证呢
What if she doesn't have a FOID?
去申请  30天就能批下来
Apply for one. You'll have a gun in 30 days.
如果她等不了30天呢
What if she doesn't have 30 days?
你有持枪许可证吗
Do you have a firearm owner id?
你帮她买
Then buy it for her.
失陪
Excuse me.
这是我们的突破口
That's our case.
非法枪支就是这样外流的
That's how illegal guns get out on the street.
你想买吗
So, do you want to buy it?
我们需要它吗
Do we need it?
不知道
I don't know.
你需要它吗
Do you?
我在查出庭安排时发现
I was checking on a court date and I found out.
你决定不立案
you passed on the lawsuit.
那为什么还来这里
So, what are we doing here?
10年前  一名叫杰弗里·斯佩尔曼的毒贩
Ten years ago, a drug dealer named Jeffrey Spellman
因24区的双重谋杀案而获罪
was convicted of double murder in the 24th ward.
在他的量刑听证会上
At his sentencing hearing, he threatened
他叫嚣  出狱后要杀了他的律师
to kill his lawyer when he got out.
你就是他的律师?
You were his lawyer?
我还在他上周的假释听证会上发言了
I also spoke last week at his parole hearing.
他看见你发言了?
He saw you speak?
他放了狠话
He'd made subsequent threats.
他假释出狱了吗
Has he been released?
周五才裁定
They decide on Friday.
好吧  你得买把枪
Okay. You need a gun.
问题是
No, the thing is,
我向来是支持枪支管制的先锋
I've been in the forefront of gun control my entire life.
我父亲最先把枪支管制纳入伊利诺斯宪法
My father wrote the first legislation into the Illinois constitution.
你需要一把容易上手的枪
You need something easy to shoot.
后坐力小  9毫米口径  贝雷塔枪
Light on recoil, 9mm-- a beretta.
我不该来的
No, this was a mistake.
我知道你是我老板
Look, I know you're my boss,
我遵从你的意思
and I'll do whatever you want.
但一个杀人犯看见你
You spoke at a killer's parole hearing
在他的假释听证会上发言  反对他假释出狱
and he saw you speak against his release.
事急从权
That's what I'd call a volatile situation.
听我一回  你需要一把枪
So listen to me on this. You need a gun.
这个特别工作组调查欺诈性房地产交易
It was a task force focusing on fraudulent real estate deals.
你们管这些交易叫"翻地"?
And these deals were called "Land flips"?
-是  -据你所知
- Yes. - And as you understood it,
有人试图利用欺诈手段  低价购买
there was an attempt to buy land, cheaply, through fraudulent means,
即将动工的奥运会场周围的土地
near the stadiums that were to be built for the Olympics?
是
Yes, sir.
在你管理这个工作组期间
And during the time you were heading up this task force,
查尔兹先生找上你
you were approached by Mr. Childs
让你盯着福瑞克先生  是吗
to keep an eye on Mr. Florrick, isn't that correct?
请定义一下"盯着"
Could you define "Keep an eye on"?
他暗示福瑞克先生建立工作组是别有用心
He suggested that Mr. Florrick had a hidden motive for this task force.
反对
Objection, your honor.
兰德里先生  你反对这干嘛
I have no idea why you are objecting to that, Mr. Landry.
诱导性问题
A leading question, your honor.
我大概需要个记分牌
I know I might need a scorecard here, Mr. Landry.
布罗迪先生不是站在你们那边的吗
Isn't Mr. Brody a hostile witness? Isn't he on your side?
但这仍是个诱导性问题
It's still leading, your honor.
反对无效  证人请回答
Overruled. You may answer the question.
是的
Yes.
你说"是的"  是什么意思
You may have to remind us all what that "Yes" Means.
是的  查尔兹先生暗示彼得是别有用心
Yes, Mr. Childs suggested Peter might have a hidden motive.
别有用心  是指福瑞克先生借此工作组
This hidden motive was that Mr. Florrick arranged this task force
来要挟房地产开发商向他行贿?
in order to then shake down the real estate developers for payoffs?
是的
Yes, sir.
你同意查尔兹先生的看法吗
And did you agree with Mr. Childs' estimation?
我的想法无关紧要  我只是按要求办事
My opinion was irrelevant. I did what I was asked.
谁的要求
By whom?
什么
Excuse me.
你说你是按要求办事
You said that you did what you were asked.
谁的要求呢
Who were you referring to?
这只是一种措辞方式
It was a figure of speech.
我知道  但措辞方式有它的含义
I understand, but figures of speech mean something,
那么  是谁的要求呢
so who asked you to do something:
是你的上级  福瑞克先生
Was it your boss, Mr. Florrick,
还是和你平级的查尔兹先生
or was it Mr. Childs, your peer?
查尔兹先生
Mr. Childs.
他让你干什么
What did he ask you to do?
他让我留意彼得的动向
He asked me to keep track of Peter.
他说彼得对一些案子拒绝起诉  是收了贿赂
He thought he was being bribed to dp cases.
那么这些案子现在进展如何
And so, how are these cases going now?
什么
Excuse me?
福瑞克先生让你不予起诉的那些案子
These cases that Mr. Florrick asked you to drop--
既然福瑞克不能再横加阻挠
I mean, you must be fervently pursuing them
这些案子  你们一定一查到底吧?
now that Peter Forrick is no longer around to obstruct them.
-不  -天呐  那你们怎么处理的
- No, sir. - My goodness. What happened to them?
我们没有起诉
We dropped them.
到你发问了
Your witness.
谢谢法官大人
Thank you, your honor.
事先说明
Uh, actually, just to be clear,
你是被告的小姨子  玛瑞尔?
you are the defendant's sister-in-law, Mariel?
你是说杀害我姐姐的被告?
The defendant who killed my sister?
-没错  -法官大人  这还用我反对吗
- Yes. - Your honor, do I really need to object?
加德纳先生  咱们都得有点敬业精神
We all need to perform our roles here, Mr. Gardner.
所以你还是说声"反对"吧
Yes, you need to object,and,
而我呢  得说声"反对有效"
yes, I need to sustain.
抱歉  法官大人 下不为例
I'm sorry, your honor. We won't let that happen again.
现在  我得问你一个不光彩的问题
Now, I have to ask you a question that I am not proud of.
-和性有关的  你介意吗  -不介意
-  sexual question. Do you mind? - No.
-问吧  不然我来干嘛  -好吧
- Please. That's why I'm here. - Okay.
你和被告斯威尼先生  发生过...
You and the defendant, Mr. Sweeney, had
性关系?
sexual relations?
是啊
Yeah.
-他和他妻子的妹妹有染?  -没错
- He had sex with his wife's sster? - Yeah, that's correct.
抱歉  我脸红了
Sorry. I think I'm blushing.
我来自密歇根州  从没遇到过这种事
I'm from Michigan. This is all new to me.
她很厉害
She's very good.
阿米塔小姐
Uh, Miss Armitage,
究竟是什么
What could possibly have led you
使得你和你亲姐姐的丈夫发生性关系
to sleep with your own sister's husband?
我一直有毒瘾
I struggled with addiction my whole life,
我姐姐因此与我疏远
and my sister and I were estranged over it.
我想  或许  我只是为了报复她
So I suppose I-- I don't know-- i did it just to get back at her.
而科林很乐意帮我一把
And Colin was too happy to help.
他让我做一些事  一些她妻子不肯做的事
He used to make me do things. You know, things his wife wouldn't do.
有一次  他让我绑住他的...
Like the time he had me tie up his...
请别说了  我得坐下
I think that that is enough. I'm just going to sit down.
谢谢
Thank you.
干得好  丹尼尔  真是漂亮
Great job, Daniel, just outstanding.
你看见查尔兹的表情了吗
Did you see Childs?
我想我们现在逼近核心了
I think we're getting really close now.
怎么了
What?
罗曼·别利科夫   那个我们用来威胁
Roman Belikov, the Russian mobster
安贝儿·麦迪逊的俄国暴徒
we used to threaten Amber Madison with?
他怎么了
What about him?
构不成威胁了
Not such a threat anymore.
[暴徒遇害]
安贝儿告诉查尔兹  她不愿作证
Amber told Childs that she wouldn't testify.
现在她肯定疯狂反扑我们
I guess now she'll be out for blood.
情况不容乐观啊
It's not going to be pretty.
我不去
No. I won't be there.
我明白  场面可能会很难堪
No, I understand. It might be rough.
麦迪逊什么都说得出来
Madison could say anything.
不过戈登说你最好出席
Although Golden does think it would be better if you were there,
这样法官就能看见我们...
so that he judge could see we...
戈登还说  如果我获释
Golden also says that the sheriff's department
警方会在家里安装电子监控
will be setting up electronic monitoring at the house if I am released.
-你能接受吗  -没问题
- Are you all right with that? - Yes.
但咱们约法三章
But I wanted to agree on a few things first.
你说
Okay.
家里有间佣人房  现在当储物间用
There's a maid's room. I've been using it for storage,
我会收拾干净  安置张床
but I will clear it out and put a bed in there.
此外  你可以使用主浴室
In the meantime, you can use the master bath.
我上班时  杰姬帮忙照应家里
Jackie has been helping out on weekdays while I'm at work,
我觉得应该继续让她帮忙
and I think she should continue--
接孩子们放学  做饭...
picking the kids up from school, making dinner...
还有  家里没有书房
And we don't have a study.
你那张卷轴面的书桌还在  现在闲置着
I still have your old rolltop desk; it's in storage.
我会把它搬到餐厅  如何
I will move it to the dining room. Okay?
你爱我吗
Do you love me?
爱
I do.
你对我说话的方式  就像个律师
You're sounding like a lawyer.
我本来就是律师
I am a lawyer.
你到底想和我重新开始吗
Do you ever want to be together again?
彼得  你伤我很深
Peter... I've been hurt, deeply.
我想有一天  我会痊愈  但现在...
I imagine I will heal someday, but for now...
我们慢慢来  好吗
We need a plan, okay?
好吧
Okay.
握紧  聚焦前瞄准具
The grip is still. Focus is on the front sight.
站稳了吗
Are you steady?
应该是吧
I think so.
接下来是最难的部分  扣扳机
Now the hardest part-- the trigger.
你会本能地用手掌和手腕的肌肉
There's a natural tendency for the muscles
连同手指一起用力
in the hand and wrist to move in tandem with the fingers.
你得避免这个
You need to resist that.
必须用食指单独发力扣扳机
You need to let your forefinger act independently, squeezing.
听懂了吗
Do you understand?
应该是吧
I think so.
好  放松点
And so, with almost no pressure at all,
瞄准目标的中心
concentrate on the center of your target.
为什么非得打要害
Why can't I shoot to injure?
开枪就得杀人
You pick up a gun, you shoot to kill
不然就别拿枪
or you don't pick up a gun.
他假释出狱了  那个威胁你的毒贩
He got out-- your parolee.
我知道
I know.
你使用致命的武力
You're trying to stop with deadly force
只是为了阻止他杀害你
somebody who is trying to kill you.
他一样有双亲  一样开生日派对
Somebody who has a mother, a father, birthday parties.
把他当作假想靶子  或者靶心
They're a shadow target, a bull's-eye.
你不把他们当人看
So you dehumanize them?
环境造成的
They are dehumanized.
这世界不是按你的规则运作
The world doesn't March to your drummer.
它有时很危险  很残酷
It's sometimes dangerous and cruel,
所以  慢慢地  小心地  举起武器
so slowly and carefully raise your weapon,
手指单独用力  拳头和手臂别使劲
make your finger work independently of your fist and arm,
然后缓缓地  冷漠地扣扳机
and gently and indifferently squeeze.
天呐
Oh, my God.
不赖嘛
Nice.
举枪  再来一次
Raise your arm and try again.
斯威尼先生  警方在你住所
So, um, as I was saying, Mr. Sweeney,
发现了沾了血迹和皮屑的绳子  是吗
there was blood and skin found on a rope at your house, right?
是的
Yes, that's right.
警方声明  绳子上的血液和皮屑
And, uh, this blood and skin--
与你妻子的吻合  是吗
the police say it all matched your wife. Is that right?
是的  我们喜欢自己砍柴
Yes, we like to cut our own firewood
然后用绳子捆起来
and wrap the kindling in rope,
我亲爱的卡罗琳肯定是砍柴时割伤了
And I believe my dearest Carolyn cut herself.
听上去挺合理
Yeah, that seems understandable, I get that.
那么让我冒昧问你一个问题
So, I need to ask you this, Mr. Sweeney, please excuse me.
说吧  姑娘
Go right ahead, dear.
你并未掐死你妻子  是吗
You never strangled your wife, right?
天呐  当然没有
My goodness, no.
那就好
Thank god.
那么...
So this, uh...
在这儿
...Here.
这是什么
What is this?
医院报告
Hospital report.
杀手锏来了
Here it comes.
你来反对  效果比我要好
You object-- it'll play better from you.
这一定是弄错了  是吗
This-this must be an aberration, right?
我不知道  我看不见
I don't know, I can't see it.
上面写着你妻子97年4月被送入医院
It says here that your wife was admitted to the hospital, April 1997.
反对
Objection, your honor.
此证据与案情无关  在之前的谋杀案审理中
This was excluded from the previous trial
未被采用
for relevance.
反对无效
I'll allow.
你的异议已记录在案  请坐下
Your exception is noted, counselor. Sit down.
你妻子对医务人员说了些奇怪的事
Your wife seems to have told the medical staff something extraordinary.
她说你想勒死她
She said that you tried to strangle her.
她夸大其辞了
That's a bit melodramatic.
我知道  不过我妈教导我  不懂就要问
Yes, I know it is, but my mom always used to say "When you don't know,
所以...  我在请教你
ask," So... This is me asking.
好吧
Certainly.
卡罗琳和我是窒息游戏的爱好者
Carolyn and I were practitioners of breath play.
什么是窒息游戏
I'm sorry, what is breath play?
我相信密歇根州也有这种游戏
Well, I'm sure they have it in Michigan, too, Miss Crozier.
窒息游戏是一种性游戏
Breath play is erotic asphyxiation.
卡罗琳喜欢在做爱时  感受窒息的快感
Carolyn liked the feeling of being strangled when she was having sex.
我想我还是坐下吧
Oh, I think I'd better sit down now.
到你发问了
Your witness.
好  我们发动攻势
Okay, we go on the offensive.
我不会让一个26岁的
I'm not going to let some 26-year-old
法学院毕业生压制住
law school grad get the better of me.
她在演戏
It's an act.
效果很好
Well, it's working.
既然无法证明斯威尼的清白
If we can't prove our guy is innocent,
我们就拖其他人下水
we need to shovel dirt on somebody else.
原告怎么样
What about the plaintiff?
夏洛特?  她刚失去了母亲
Charlotte? The jury felt sorry for her.
陪审团同情她  我们不能说她是凶手
She lost her mother. We can't suggest she's the killer.
把矛头对准死者妹妹玛瑞尔
Go after the sister Mariel, suggest she was the killer.
陪审团也喜欢她
The jury liked her, too.
不是喜欢她  只是相信她
They didn't like her, they believed her.
继续说
I'm listening.
玛瑞尔嫉妒她姐姐
Mariel was jealous of her sister.
她和斯威尼上床  是为了报复她姐姐
She slept with Sweeney to get back at her.
根据我的经验
In my experience,
这种极端的嫉妒  不会轻易化解
that level of jealousy just doesn't end.
警察验证过她的不在场证明吗
Did the cops even check her alibi?
她自称卡罗琳失踪时正在戒毒所里
Supposedly she was in rehab when Carolyn disappeared.
好  传讯她的证词  艾丽西娅
Okay, get a subpoena for the records, and, Alicia,
要推翻玛瑞尔的不在场证明
if we're tearing down the sister's alibi,
我们得证明斯威尼的不在场证明
we need to shore up Sweeney's.
-真有意思  -那是
- How fun. - Yep,
目前你可是斯威尼的经纪人
you're the Sweeney wrangler these days.
跟你说了  我当时正从圣路易斯驾车回家
I told you I was in my car on the drive back from St. Louis.
没有导航仪  也没手机?
With no gps and no cell phone?
你喜欢日本漫画吗
You like manga?
我觉得它们的画风非常率真
I find the style bracingly visceral.
你没在从圣路易斯回家的路上  是吧
You weren't on your way back from St. Louis, were you?
没错
No.
你知道我们要输了吗
Do you know that we're losing?
我知道
Yes.
那就别扯谎  别分散我的注意力
So no stories, no lies, no diversions.
你到底在哪
Where were you?
马可  这是我的律师
Marco, this is my lawyer.
你告诉她  我妻子失踪那天我在哪里
I need you to tell her where I was the day my wife disappeared.
我和往常一样3:30左右到这来
I got here about 3:30 like I always do.
随后你就来买大烟
You rolled up after that, looking to score some opie.
就是鸦片  有时和肉末混着吃
Opium, sometimes mixed with hash.
现在知道我为何不告诉你了吧
Now you see why I didn't tell you before?
真不是你做的?
So you didn't do it?
杀卡罗琳吗  没有
Kill Carolyn? No.
那你那些把戏和笑话是为了什么
Then why all the games and the jokes?
两位让让
Do you guys mind?
我还要做生意
I'm working here.
你知道我何时开始
You know when I started getting
能在餐厅坐上最好的位置吗
the best tables in restaurants?
正是人们以为我杀妻的那天
The day they thought I killed my wife.
这值得吗
Is that really worth
就为了餐厅最好的座位?
getting the best tables in restaurants?
当然值得
Of course.
和你一样  人们从此对我忌惮三分
Why do you look at me the way you do?
我的照片
Why is my picture
出现在《芝加哥太阳时报》头版
on the front page of the Chicago Sun-times?
八卦杂志刊登我昨晚看了哪场戏
Why does page six care what play I saw last night?
如果妻子死了  而大家都认为是你干的
If your wife is dead, and everyone thinks you did it,
证明我杀没杀她有什么意义呢
well, really, what's the difference?
克罗泽小姐
Miss Crozier.
你好
Hello?
Oh, hi.
抱歉我忘了你的名字
I'm sorry, I've forgotten your name.
艾丽西娅·福瑞克
Alicia Florrick.
幸会
Right, nice to see you.
我真的希望今天可以谈妥
I really hope that we can make a deal today.
我很讨厌法庭上的争斗
I just hate this courtroom fighting.
威尔建议我们先谈着
Yes, well, Will suggested that we get started,
他一会就过来
and he will join us later.
你在法庭上表现得很好
You're doing very well in court.
没觉得  我还是个新手
Oh, I don't know about that. I'm just a beginner.
不  你不是
Hmm, no, you're not.
这话怎么讲
Why do you say that?
因为我觉得你很清楚自己在做什么
Because I think you know exactly what you're doing.
我倒想呢
I wish I did.
你的证人玛瑞尔
Your witness Mariel--
在谋杀当晚  没有不在场证据
She doesn't have an alibi the night of the murder.
她4点离开戒毒所
She left rehab at 4:00.
然后因为嫉妒赶去杀掉姐姐吗
And what, rushed over to kill her sister out of jealousy?
这种事常有
Been known to happen.
陪审团不讨厌她
The jury didn't hate her.
他们讨厌你的客户
They hated your client.
我们和斯威尼先生谈过
We spoke to Mr. Sweeney.
他愿意分你客户一半遗产
He's willing to offer your client 50% of the estate.
不行
No.
他害夏洛特失去母亲
Charlotte lost her mother to Sweeney.
他没有资格得到遗产
He has to walk away from the estate.
她每年会给他生活费  每次不超过30万
She'll offer him a yearly stipend-- low six figures.
不行
No.
斯威尼先生有不在场证明
Mr. Sweeney has an alibi.
肯定很可靠吧
Well, I'm sure it's a good one.
要证明它的真实性  过程一定很有趣
It'll be fun to try and prove it.
看来没什么可谈的了
I guess we don't have anything to talk about, then.
但见到你很高兴
But it was nice to meet you.
我真喜欢你的外套
And I really love your jacket.
我妈妈有件一模一样的
My mom has one just like it.
今晚热点  是卡罗琳·阿米塔失踪案的
Our top story tonight involves the shocking developments
令人震惊的案情进展
in the Carolyn Armitage disappearance case.
警察怀疑
Police strongly suspect
阿米塔的遗骸已被发现
that Armitage's remains have been uncovered.
今晨  一位建筑工
A construction crew made the grisly discovery this morning
在科林·斯威尼原住所的院子里发现部分骸骨
in the courtyard of Colin Sweeney's penthouse apartment,
此处在他妻子失踪后即被售出
A residency sold after the disappearance of his wife.
骸骨在花园被浅土掩埋
The remains, which were found in a shallow grave
尚未做身份鉴定
in the flower garden, have yet to be identified,
但调查人员相信它属于卡罗琳
But investigators believe they belong to the missing Carolyn Armitage.
我不知为何感觉很糟
I don't know why I feel bad.
-至少我们确定是他干的了  -是
- At least we know for certain now he did it. - Yep,
而我们还要继续为他辩护
and we're still defending him.
《芝加哥报》指出  千夫所指的科林
...Chicago Society figure, Colin Sweeney,
完全有可能是谋杀犯
a man who many believe is entirely capable of murder.
少来这套
Oh, don't even try it.
少来哪套?
What?
鳄鱼的眼泪
To patronize me with your tears.
我知道很不可思议
I thought somewhere in the back of my mind--
但我其实一直暗存希望
and I will admit that it made no sense--
卡罗琳可能还活着
Carolyn might be still alive.
就像漫画里的肯·雷  假死脱身
Like Ken Lay, faking his own death, and hopping off
躲到某个小岛上
to a small island somewhere.
你是说  你和此事无关吗
So you're saying you had nothing to do with this?
我是做过许多错事  我承认
I'm saying I've done some terrible things in my life. I have.
但我没杀我妻子
But I did not kill my wife.
那她为何被埋在你的院子里
Then how did her skull end up buried in your backyard?
有人栽赃
Someone put it there!
彼得
Peter's the sort of man
是个希望凡事都由别人为他安排好的人
who expects things to be handed to him.
包括我在内
Like I was.
-你们是约在酒店吗  -是的
- This was at the hotel? - Yes.
我订了间房
I had a room.
他打电话给他妻子  说会晚归
He called his wife, said he'd be late.
完事后  他会约我下次见面
And then afterwards, he asked me if he could see me again.
你们见了多少次
How many times?
很多次  持续了几个月
Two dozen. It went on for months.
有时候一周2  3次
Sometimes two, three times a week.
-他知道有人买单?  -是的
- And he knew you were being provided to him? - Yes.
完事后  我会打电话要求付款
Afterwards, I would make a call in order to be paid.
打电话时他也在场
He heard me make those calls.
福瑞克夫人
Mrs. Florrick.
...他有说过要回报你的...
...Say anything about having to do something in return for your...
不进去吗
Would you like to come in?
服务吗?
services?
是的
Yes.
他说那些买单的人官司缠身
He told me that the men who paid me had cases against them.
他说会关照他们的案子
He understood that he had to do something about those cases.
关照?
"Do something"?
就是让它们不了了之
Oh, um, make them go away.
他还拿这事开玩笑
He laughed about it, actually.
说在芝加哥办事  就得付出这种代价
said that was the price of doing business in Chicago.
到你发问了
Your witness.
麦迪逊女士  你说福瑞克知道
Ms. Madison, you say that Mr. Florrick knew
有人替他付钱?
that someone else was paying for your services?
是的
Yes.
那么  为何他自己还要付钱给你
Then,why would he pay you as well?
他从没付钱
He never did.
你知道这是什么吗
Do you... recognize this?
不
No.
这是银行记录
It's bank records
户主是洛蕾塔·克里斯宾斯基
from an account in the name of Loretta Krispinsky.
这是你的真名  对吧
That is your real name, isn't it?
这个账户  前阵子被注销了
Now, this particular account was closed some time ago,
但交易记录还在
But the transactions are there.
多次有固定金额3500美元存入账户
Repeated deposits in the amount of $3,500.
而福瑞克先生的一个私人账户
Now, these are records from one of Mr. Florrick's personal accounts,
有相应的提款记录  金额也是3500
with corresponding withdrawals in the same amount of $3,500.
通常在你存款前的1到2天内
Always within a day or two of when you deposited the money.
我得提醒你  你是对庭宣誓过的
Now, I'm going to remind you that you're under oath,
麦迪逊女士  或者该叫克里斯宾斯基女士?
Ms. Madison, or should I say, ms. Krispinsky?
有两方付钱给你
You were paid twice.
-对吗 -不是
- Isn't that correct? - No.
有求于福瑞克的人付钱让你陪他
You were paid by your procurers, who thought that
以为他接受了他们的贿赂
they were bribing Mr. Florrick for your services,
而福瑞克先生也付钱给你
and you were also paid by Mr. Florrick,
他根本不知道有别人付账
who didn't know that you were being paid by others.
是这样吗
Isn't that correct?
这不过是个巧合  你歪曲事实
You can make numbers look like anything you want.
不  没人能歪曲事实
Well, actually... you can't.
我问完了  法官大人
I have no further questions for this witness, your honor.
我想我们已经见识了安贝儿·麦迪逊了
I think we've had quite enough of Amber Madison.
我翻查了斯威尼的妻子在失踪那天早上
I've been going over the books Sweeney's wife demanded to
要求查看的帐本
see the morning she disappeared,
看看这个
and look at this.
蕾马特  什么东西
Renmart? What's that?
夏洛特·阿米塔成立的一间皮包公司
It's a dummy corporation Charlotte Armitage set up.
所以我把账本和其它线索对照了一下
So I cross-referenced the books against the other discovery,
看看这个
and look at this.
玛瑞尔·阿米塔最近屡进戒毒所
Mariel Armitage has been in rehab several times recently,
全部由她亲爱的外甥女夏洛特买单
all paid for by her loving niece, Charlotte.
大家都以为卡罗琳
Now, everybody thought Carolyn was angry
是气斯威尼乱花钱
about the money Sweeney had been spending.
但或许她真正气的是夏洛特
Maybe she was really angry at Charlotte.
我跟我妈妈的关系?
My relationship with my mother?
她是我的挚友
She was my best friend.
你能告诉我蕾马特是什么吗
And can you tell me what Renmart is?
法官大人  我想我得提出反对
Your honor, I think I might have to object here.
这问题与本案无关
my only concern is relevance.
科里  不是让你给门轴上点润滑油吗
Cory, I thought we were gonna get some WD-40 on those hinges.
反对无效
Overruled.
法官大人
Your honor...
我说了  反对无效
I said, overruled.
蕾马特是什么
So, what is Renmart?
那是我几年前成立的一家公司
It was a company I started a few years ago.
我住在农场里
I live on a farm.
计划自产自销有机果酱和果冻
I was going to market a line of organic jams and jellies.
你从家庭信托中取了一大笔钱
And you withdrew a fair amount of money
来投资这个水果站  是吗
from the family trust to fund this fruit stand, didn't you?
我妈妈首肯的
My mother okayed that.
你妈妈消失后
But even after your mother disappeared,
你还是继续提款  是这样吗
you continued withdrawing money, isn't that correct?
然而你从未生产出一罐果酱
Yet you never produced a single jar of jam.
你的公司没有实际地址
Your company has no physical address,
只有一个租用信箱
except a P.O. Box.
也没有实际的财产
No assets except a bank account
只有一个活期账户
that you can access any time you'd like.
反对  法官大人
Objection... Your honor.
反对理由是?
On what grounds?
让我查查看
Let me look here.
好吧  你查你的
Yeah, well, while you're looking,
反对无效
overruled.
你把钱寄给在戒毒的小姨
You were sending money away to your aunt in rehab,
但你不想让你妈妈知道
and you didn't want your mother to know.
不是这样的
That is not true.
卡罗琳知道你这么做吗
So Carolyn was aware you were doing this?
不知道  不是
No... I mean...
一开始不知道  但
No, not-not at first, but...
但后来她发现了  很生气?
And when she found out, she was angry?
厩腐蝇
Muscina stabulans.
一种蛆?
A maggot?
不是普通的蛆
Not just any maggot.
它通常寄居在乡下的牲畜身上
This little fellow is usually found in rural areas, often near livestock,
但这条却被埋在斯威尼原来的院子里
but this was buried in the courtyard of Sweeney's old apartment.
真正奇怪的是  它居然还在遗骸上
What's even more unusual is that it's here at all.
尸体上有蛆  不是很正常吗
Why wouldn't a maggot be found on a corpse?
有肉吃  它才待得住
Oh, it would, as long as there was flesh to eat.
但时隔两年  本不该有残留的人体组织
But after two years, I'd expect to find a clean skull.
头颅上还残留着大量人体组织
A head with so much tissue still preserved suggests
说明土壤中有污染物  通常是铅或砷
contaminants in the soil-- usually lead or arsenic.
砷原本被用于杀虫剂  是吧
Arsenic was used in pesticides, right?
70年代才被禁止
Until they banned it in the 1970s.
但若在被禁前使用过含砷杀虫剂
But if it was used before that,
土壤中仍然会残留污染物
there'd still be concentrations of it in the soil.
而农场上会使用这种杀虫剂  对吧
Pesticides like those used on a farm?
或许吧  怎么了
Maybe. Why?
猜猜谁住在乡下农场  又近牲畜
Guess who lives on a farm in a rural area, near livestock?
别告诉我  你就是凶手
Don't tell me. You're the killer.
谢谢  李  你帅呆了
Thanks, Li. You're a prince.
正义(狗名)  过来
Justice! Come here.
你真是
Oh! You...
天啊
Oh, god.
有发现
Found something!
卡罗琳·阿米塔尸体的其余部分
The rest of Carolyn Armitage's remains were discovered
在其女夏洛特的农场院子里被挖出
buried behind the new Caledonia farm of Charlotte Armitage, her daughter.
夏洛特被当场拘捕
Arrested at the scene was Charlotte Armitage.
你们不懂吗  他陷害我
Don't you see?! He set me up!
我没有...  不是我干的
I didn't... I didn't do this!
他栽赃嫁祸
He put her body here!
他谋财害命
He killed her for her money!
他陷害我  不是我干的
He set me up! I didn't do it!
你们  你们看不出来吗
Don't you... Don't you see?!
给我们一点时间  好吗
Give us a moment, okay?
-鸡肉三明治?  -不用
- Chicken sandwich? - No.
我跟你做个交易
I have an offer to make.
洗耳恭听
I can't wait.
明天你可以回家  获得自由
Tomorrow, you can go home, free.
我会以人道主义理由提请释放你
I'll argue for your release on humanitarian grounds.
你应该跟家人团聚
You should be home with your family.
为什么帮我
Why would you do that?
因为我是一名人道主义者
Because I'm a humanitarian.
交换条件是什么
What's the catch?
这算不上交换条件
The catch is hardly worthy of its name.
让罪名成立
The conviction stands.
你心知肚明  你的确拒绝起诉那几个案子
You know you DP'd those cases, Peter.
现在只有我和你
Now, it's just you and I here.
我们可以坦诚相对
We can admit our feelings to each other.
-你想让我承认有罪?  -对
- You want me to let the guilty verdict stand? - Yes.
候审时间折抵刑期  你明天就能回家
with time served, you'd go home tomorrow.
-我的律师资格无法恢复?  -对
- And my disbarment stands? - Yes.
我再也不能做你的竞选对手?
And I can never run against you?
不错
That's right.
你没有机会  彼得  你知道的
You have no chance, Peter. You realize that.
如果我没有机会  你来干嘛
If I have no chance, what are you doing here?
好吧  你听我说
Okay, you know what?
总有一天  我们得放下冤仇
At a certain point, this has to move beyond retribution.
我们俩都是
For both of us.
你得考虑一下你的家人
You have to think about your family
或者冒险上诉
or risk a failed appeal
然后在牢里多呆九年
and another nine years in prison,
出狱时你该几岁了  彼得
and how old will you be then, Peter?
你的小孩又几岁了
How old will your kids be?
生日派对  男朋友  大学毕业
Birthday parties, boyfriends, college graduations--
都在你坐牢时一一错过
While you were in prison.
你在牢中逐渐老朽  而生活仍在继续
A life lived while you grow old in prison.
你选吧  彼得  是明天就回家
Now, that's the deal, Peter, go home tomorrow
还是冒再受9年牢狱之苦的险
or risk nine more years in prison. Hmm?
你好好想想吧
You think about it.
你拿走吧
I need you to take it.
我觉得  不自在
I don't feel... comfortable anymore.
锻炼一下就好了
You can be made to feel comfortable.
不用了
I don't think so.
你害怕枪
You're scared of it?
不
No.
我开始喜欢
I'm liking it.
-我先帮你保管  -不
- I'll hold it for you. - No.
我不会改变主意
I'm not going to change my mind.
我会把账单寄给你
I'll send you my bill.
正合我意
I expect no less.
福瑞克夫人  我给你带了礼物
Mrs. Florrick. I brought you something.
聊表敬意
A token of my esteem.
我觉得  不知为何  它异常适合你
I thought it, somehow, strangely appropriate for you.
是你干的  对吧
You did it, didn't you?
我干了什么
Did what?
杀了她  你妻子
Killed her. Your wife.
然后把她埋在夏洛特的院子里
And then you buried her in Charlotte's yard.
如果我栽赃
If I did that,
为何偏偏把头骨留在自己院子里
why would I leave the skull in my yard?
为了把我们引向夏洛特
To point us to Charlotte.
你太多疑了  福瑞克夫人
You're being paranoid, Mrs. Florrick.
有时候事情真相就和表面一样
Sometimes things are as they seem.
不可能的事
The unlikely maneuver is exactly that--
就是不可能
Unlikely.
我要走了
I have to go.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你需要信任别人
You just have to trust people.
希望你喜欢这幅画
Enjoy the picture.